A story of being lost... and found.
Cry Macho is a drama, western film directed by Clint Eastwood.
A one-time rodeo star and washed-up horse breeder takes a job from an
ex-boss to bring the man's young son home from Mexico.
Mike Milo, played by Clint Eastwood.
Rafo, played by Eduardo Minett.
Marta, played by Natalia Traven.
Howard Polk, played by Dwight Yoakam.
Leta, played by Fernanda Urrejola.
Aurelio, played by Horacio García Rojas.
Cry Macho is a 2021 American neo-Western drama film directed,  produced by
and starring Clint Eastwood and written by Nick Schenk and N.
Richard Nash, based on Nash's 1975 novel.
Set in 1979, it stars Eastwood as a former rodeo star hired to reunite a young boy
(Eduardo Minett) in Mexico with his father (Dwight Yoakam) in the United States.
There were many attempts to adapt Nash's novel into a film over the years.
Arnold Schwarzenegger came on board to star in
2011, but canceled after a scandal.
In 2020, Eastwood's adaptation was announced; he
produced the film with Albert S.
Ruddy (in his final film before his death), Tim Moore, and Jessica Meier.
Cry Macho was filmed from November to December 2020 in the state of New Mexico; Ben Davis was the
cinematographer, Mark Mancina was the composer, and Joel and David Cox were the editors.
It was theatrically released in the United States on
September 17, 2021, by Warner Bros.
Pictures with a simultaneous 31-day release on the HBO Max streaming service.
The film underperformed at the box office, grossing $16
million against a $33 million budget.
It received mixed reviews, with its cinematography and calm style of storytelling and score receiving praise
while the screenplay was targeted for criticism; Eastwood's performance drew polarized responses.
The film explores themes of mexico, based on novel or
book, kidnapping, 1970s, neo-western.
The tone is emotional.